Wiggs mss., 1874-1936 LMC 2120
Lilly Library
Wiggs mss.
1874-1936
Lilly Library
Wiggs, George Washington, 1853-1938
LMC 2120
32 Items 1 box; 1 folio
The Wiggs mss., 1874-1936, are the papers of George Washington Wiggs, 1853-1938, grain dealer on the Chicago Board of Trade, member of the Press Club of Chicago, and an Indiana University graduate of 1874.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
George Washington Wiggs, 1853-1938, was a grain dealer on the Chicago Board of Trade, a member of the Press Club of Chicago, and an Indiana University graduate of 1874.
Scope and Content Note
The Wiggs mss., 1874-1936, are the papers of George Washington Wiggs, 1853-1938, grain dealer on the Chicago Board of Trade, member of the Press Club of Chicago, and an Indiana University graduate of 1874. In the collection are Wiggs' oration, No Rest, given at the 45th annual commencement, July 2, 1874; the printed program on that occasion; and his diploma signed by all of his instructors, including Sarah Parke Morrison, the first woman faculty member of the university. Photographs include those of George Washington Wiggs and of his wife, Anna (Oldfield) Wiggs, author of the novel Apple-blossoms.
The correspondents are John McGovern, editor of The Current in which Wiggs had an interest; Henry Lew Pond, at one time an officer of Delta Tau Delta; Anna (Oldfield) Wiggs; and George Washington Wiggs, who wrote to his father in 1885 and 1889.
Many of the pieces are accompanied by explanatory notes by Neal O. Hines.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 1985.
Women; Wiggs, George Washington, 1853-1938
- Biographical material (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1885-1936 (Box 1)
  - George [Washington Wiggs] to his father [Felix G. Wiggs]. Carbon, 1885, July 20 (Box 1)
  - Letterhead of Geo. W. Wiggs & Co., Chicago, Ill. for Bill of sale form. Blank, 189- (Box 1)
  - Invitation to meet President Theodore Roosevelt at the Press Club of Chicago. Printed. Geo. W. Wiggs listed as an Active Member, 1902, Oct. 3 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trade of the City of Chicago. Member's ticket No. 760 for Wiggs. Signed by Geo. F. Stone, secretary, Walter S. Blowney, asst. sec. D.S., 1907, Dec. 19 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trade...Chicago. Member's Special Assessment ticket for Wiggs, No. 1535. Signed by Stone & Blowney. D.S., 1907, Dec. 19 (Box 1)
  - Press Club of Chicago. Card for privileges of the Ladies Dept.of the Press Club, extended to the family of Geo. W. Wiggs. Two cards. Signed by E. W. Pickard, sec. D.S., 1909, Sept. 11 (Box 1)
  - John McGovern to George W. Wiggs. A.L.S. 1p. 15.2cm. Enclosing Peroration of Wilbur and Orville, A.D. 4pp. 15.2cm. Page 1 is on verso of the letter. McGovern says this is the "original composition" of the work., 1910, May 24 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trade...Chicago. Member's ticket, No. 1519 for Wiggs. Signed by J.C.T. Merrill, pres., Geo. F. Stone, sec., Walter S. Blowney, asst. sec. D.S., 1911, Nov. 3 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trade...Chicago. Member's Special Assessment ticket, No. 1474 for Wiggs. Signed by Stone and Blowney. D.S., 1911, Nov. 3 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trade...Chicago. Member ticket, No. 1490 for Wiggs, until Sept. 1, 1912. Signed by Francis M. Bunch, Pres., Stone, sec., 1912, July 5 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trade...Chicago. Member ticket, No. 627 for Wiggs, until Jan. 6, 1913. Signed by Bunch and Stone. D.S., 1912, July 5 (Box 1)
  - Press Club of Chicago. Certificate of honorary membership for Wiggs. Signed by Chas. N. Wheeler, pres., W. Frederick Nutt, sec. D.S., 1912, Sept. 14 (Box 1)
  - Press Club of Chicago. Membership card No. 1098 for Wiggs. Signed by B. Beecher Osborne, financial secretary. D.S., 1912, Third quarter. (Box 1)
  - Henry L[ewis] Pond to Geo. W. Wiggs. T.L.S. 1p. 26.5cm. Enclosing brief history of Delta Tau Delta at Indiana University, carbon of T.D. 2pp. 24cm., 1931, Apr. 18 (Box 1)
  - Henry L[ewis] Pond to Geo. W. Wiggs. T.L.S. 1p. 27.5cm. Regarding Delta Tau Delta at Indiana University., 1936, Aug. 13 (Box 1)
  - (2) [Wiggs, Anna Oldfield] To [White, Louella?] AL's (both 6p. fragments), n.d. [ca. 1888] (Box 1)
  - Wiggs, Geo[rge] W[ashington] To [Wiggs, Felix G] T(carbon)L., 1889, Jan. 18 (Box 1)
- Writings (Box 1)
  - [McGovern, John]. The Emery Wheel, Sparks. n.d. A.D. 30pp. 8cm. Arranged by first line, beginning: "After you have taken away...." Statements about beauty and joy. Probably for publication in The Current, Chicago literary weekly in which Wiggs had an interest (Box 1)
  - [McGovern, John]. [The Emery Wheel, Sparks]. n.d. A.D. 13pp. 8cm. Arranged by first line, beginning: "Beauty may be for itself alone...." (Box 1)
  - Wiggs, Anna Oldfield. [Diary] A.D., 1887, Oct. 25-1888, Apr. 5 (Box 1)
  - Wiggs, Anna Oldfield.What a piano saw [short story] n.d. T.D.S. 19p. (Box 1)
  - Wiggs, George Washington (Box 1)
    - Memories. Poem of 31 lines. n.d. Printed, not published (Hines letter 2-8-85) (Box 1)
    - My Prayer. Poem of 28 lines. n.d. Printed, not published (Hines letter 2-8-85) (Box 1)
    - My Youth and I. Poem of 11 verses, 4 lines each, n.d. A.D. 4pp. 24cm. Written on stationery of Lexington Hotel, Chicago. (Box 1)
    - Wiggs, Geo. W.No Rest. A.D. 7pp. 25cm. Oration bears an additional date of Accompanied by program for 45th annual commencement of Indiana State University, Bloomington, at which the oration was rendered by Wiggs. Program printed by T.C. Pursel., [18]74, July 2; [18]76, Aug. 3 (Box 1)
- Photographs (Box 1)
  - Wiggs, Anna (Oldfield), (Mrs. George Washington Wiggs). Photograph by O.D. Scott of 2220 Indiana Avenue, Chicago, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Wiggs, George Washington. Photograph. n.d. Probably as an Indiana University student, 1870-1874. (Box 1)
  - Wiggs, George Washington. Photograph. Wearing hat and with cigar in hand, ca. 1885 (Box 1)
  - G.W. Wiggs residence at 3647 South Michigan Avenue, Chicago. 3 views House occupied by the Wiggs family, ca. 1885-1895., 1963 (Box 1)
  - Wiggs, Anna (Oldfield), n.d. [ca. 1900] (Box 1)
  - Wiggs, Bertha, n.d. [ca. 1900] (Box 1)
  - Wiggs, George Washington, n.d. [Early 1930s] (Box 1)
- Printed materials, (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - The Current, (Vol. I, No. 1). First page only. Xerox from University of Washington, Nortwest Collection., Saturday December 22, 1883 (Box 1)
  - The Current, Easter issue (Vol. V, No. 123). pages 257-288. Xerox from The Chicago Public Library. Issue contains Apple-blossoms--IX by Anna Oldfield Wiggs, April 24, 1886 (Box 1)
  - Riley, James Whitcomb.The Old Swimmin'-hole, and 'Leven More Poems. 6th edition. Indianapolis, The Bowen-Merrill Co., 1888. Lilly Library has 5 copies of this edition, all with individual hard covers (Lilly PS2704.O42 1888). This copy has paper covers. No inscriptions (Box 1)
  - Sesamus...Special Number...Summer Solstice, Mimeo. 33p., 1938 (Box 1)
- Diploma awarded to G.W. Wiggs at the 45th annual commencement at Indiana University at Bloomington for the Bachelor of Science degree. D.S. 1p. 39.5cm. On vellum, gold seal. Signed by Amzi Atwater, Elisha Ballantine, Hermann B[althasar] Boisen, Geo[rge] W[ashington] Hose, Daniel Kirkwood, Sarah P[arke] Morrison, Cyrus Nutt, Ricardus [sic] Owen, James Thompson, Theophilus A[dam] Wylie (Ovflat 17)